Rika! Rika! Oh no! This is a disaster!
（羽入(はにゅう)）梨花(りか) 梨花！
大変なのです 一大事なのですう！
What are you going on about in here, Hanyuu?
（梨花）
なあに？ 羽入 こんな所で
（羽入）
あぅあぅ これを見るのです
Look at this!
Hm? One of the legs of this incense burner is broken.
（梨花）
あら この香炉 脚が欠けてるわね
Your ancestors used this as an offering
when they were sealing a certain thing...
（羽入）
この香炉は 梨花のご先祖様が―
あるものを封印した時に
お供えしたものなのです
これが壊れたということは 封印が
解けてしまったということなのです
If this has broken, it means the seal has come undone!
Isn't that, like, a really bad thing?
それって すごくまずいことなの？
It's all in this scroll - with illustrations, too!
（羽入）
この巻物に書いてありますのです
イラスト付きなのですよ
"The forbidden treasure, the Jewels of Accord, is a terrible treasure from hell left to us by our god."
“門外不出の至宝
フワラズの勾玉(まがたま)は―”
“鬼神の残したる地獄の至宝なり”
“人里に現れることあらば
鬼たちが人々に取りつき―”
"Should it appear in the human world, the demons will possess the bodies of people and lead them to the gates of Pandemonium".
“阿鼻叫喚の地獄絵図と
なるものなり” あっ
Does that mean there'll be a massive outbreak of final-stage symptoms?!
ということは
末期発症の集団発生ってことなの？
If used properly, it has a wonderful power. However, it was so
dangerous, your ancestors sealed it away far off beyond the sky.
正しく使えば
すばらしい力があるのですが―
あまりに危険なので
梨花のご先祖様が―
遠いお空の向こうに封印したのです
Beyond the sky... you mean, if the seal breaks,
it'll come falling down somewhere in the village?
空の向こう… ってことは―
封印が解けたら 村のどこかへ
落下してくるってわけ？
誰かが拾ってしまったら
大変なことになるのですう
If someone were to pick it up, it would be terrible!
（梨花）大変なこと？
（羽入）はぅ～！
Terrible...?
Shall I let you in on a secret?
教えましょうか
Oshiemashou ka?
In return, promise me you won't tell anyone else
その代わり誰にも　言わない約束してね
Sono kawari dare ni mo iwanai yakusoku shite ne
Hold your little finger to mine and swear, lie and it's a thousand needles
指切りげんまん　嘘ついたら針千本
Yubikiri genman, uso tsuitara hari senbon
Take the convoluted story
折りたたまれたまま蠢いている物語を
Oritatamareta mama ugomeiteiru monogatari wo
spread it out and show it to me
広げて見せてよ
Hirogete misete yo
The past and the future are
過去も未来も
Kako mo mirai mo
a superscription of data
Super scription of data
Day Breaking Chapter
I could kill...
（圭一(けいいち)）殺せる
俺は このレナ特製
手作りクッキーのためなら―
For Rena's home-made cookies, I could kill a man without a moment's hesitation!
容赦なく人が殺せる んがあ…
あむっ んっ んっ んっ
（レナ）ンフフッ
I'm not sure I like the metaphor, but I'm glad to hear that.
（レナ）例えは ひどいけど
うれしいかな かな
んっ んで 今日の
宝の山の戦果はどうだったんだ？
So, how'd things go with the treasure pile today?
ん… 明日以降に期待かな
明日も圭一君 来てくれる？
I'll need to go back again another day. Will you come along tomorrow?
Or will you not come unless I bring... cookies?
それとも
クッキー作ってないとダメ？
All right! All right! I'll help, so don't look at me like that!
わ… 分かったよ
手伝うから そんな目で見んな！
はぅ～ 圭一君と一緒なら
何も出てこなくても楽しいよ
If I'm with Keiichi-kun, it's fun even if we don't find anything.
（圭一）うわっ ちょ… まぶしい
（レナ）うっ
So bright!
（富竹(とみたけ)）ハハハッ
（圭一）あっ
That's a nice shot of smiling kids in street clothes!
（富竹）至福の笑顔 いただき
T-Tomitake-san? And Takano-san, too?
（圭一）
と… 富竹さん それに鷹野(たかの)さんも
（鷹野）フフフッ ジロウさんも
デリカシーのない人よね
Going and ruining your date like that...
Jirou-san really has no delicacy, does he?
レナちゃんたちのデートに
水を差すなんて
いっ デートじゃない
デートじゃない！
This isn't a date! It's not!
Ah, don't worry about it. By spending time
together, you're strengthening your bonds.
いや いいんだ いいんだ
こういう時を重ねながら
２人は絆を強めていくんだよ
ねっ？ 鷹野さん
（鷹野）うん？ アハハッ
Right, Takano-san?
Strengthening our bonds? Rena and Keiichi-kun are strengthening our bo-
絆を強めていく？
（圭一）あっ
レナと圭一君が絆を強めて…
は… はぅ～！
レナ 赤くなるな！
Rena, don't blush! If you start blushing now, it's going to get really awkward!
そこで赤くなられると
非常に気まずい！
はぅ～ 絆を強めていくう！
Strengthening our bonds...!!
（せき込み）
（圭一）おい どうした？ レナ
Hey, what's wrong, Rena?
（鷹野）何か飲み込んだみたいよ
It looks like she swallowed something!
（せき込み）
（レナ）ハア
Hmm? I feel a bit better, now.
あれ？ すっきりしちゃった
（圭一）大丈夫か？
Are you all right?
うん もう何ともないよ
Yeah. I'm fine.
Do you think you should go to the clinic to have the director take a look, just in case?
念のため診療所で―
監督に診てもらったほうが
いいんじゃないのか？
Thanks. If I don't feel well tomorrow, I'll do that.
んっ ありがとう
明日になって
具合が悪かったら そうするね
（鷹野）そう よかった
なら行きましょう ジロウさん
Is that so? I'm glad to hear that.
Then let's go, Jirou-san. We mustn't get in their way any longer.
いつまでも２人の邪魔しちゃ悪いわ
（圭一）いっ…
（富竹）アハハッ そ… そうだね
Y-Yeah, you're right. See ya!
（圭一）いや…
（富竹）じゃ
Getting in our way? What do they mean by that?
邪魔って
どういうことかな？ かな？
Calm down, Rena! Calm down!
（圭一）お… 落ち着け レナ
落ち着くんだ！
あっ いや だから
赤くなるな！ 赤くなるなって！
Don't blush! Don't!
レナ とにかく落ち着け！
Rena! Calm down!
（羽入）あぅ！
間違いなく この辺りなのです
It's definitely nearby!
波動を感じますのですよ
I can feel its aura!
The Jewels of Accord were originally marriage jewels.
フワラズの勾玉は
もともとは縁結びの勾玉なのです
If you wear one of these red and white jewels and give the other one to the person of your dreams, you'll end up a couple in mutual love.
紅白１組の勾玉を
意中の人と持ち合うと―
相思相愛になれる
ラブラブアイテムなのです
It's that kind of love-love item!
あぅあぅ～！
（梨花）あれなの？
Is that it?
Seal
It's an empty box...
空箱ね
So the red and white jewels were held in these depressions...
このくぼみに紅白２つの勾玉が
収められていたというわけ？
The jewels may have fallen nearby! Let's look for them!
勾玉は この近くに
落ちているのかもしれません
捜しましょうなのです！
そう なら
あんたの妖気アンテナで…
Well, let's use your aura antenna then!
The aura transmitter was attached to the box! This is the only thing it can find!
妖気発信機は
箱のほうに取りつけられていて―
これ以上は捜せないのです
どうすんのよ こんな所で！
Then what do you expect me to do out here?!
無理 絶対無理！
捜せっこないわ！
I give up! It's hopeless! There's no way to find them here!
You're useless! Useless! Usele-!
（梨花）この役立たず！
役立たず！ 立たず！
（魅音(みおん)）
フフン おじさんの見たところ
あれは恋だね
To this old man's eyes, this can only be one thing: Love.
L-Love, you say?!
（沙都子(さとこ)）ここ… 恋ですって!?
Seriously? I can't help but think it must be because of that weird thing she swallowed yesterday...
そうか？
俺は 昨日飲み込んじまった
妙なもんのせいだと思うんだけど…
妙なものって何ですの？
Weird thing? Like what?
んっ？ ああ 昨日さ―
Ah, yesterday, when we were out looking for treasure, something fell
from the sky and went "plop!" right into her mouth and she swallowed it.
宝探しに行って
何か空から降ってきて―
そいつがスポンと口の中に入って
飲み込んじゃったんだよ
She swallowed something that fell from the sky?
空から落ちてきたものを
飲み込んだ!?
あぅあぅ～ レナの中に
赤の勾玉があるのです
The red jewel is inside her!
The power of the jewel has taken hold of her!
（羽入）勾玉の力が
レナに宿ってしまっているのです
ローブローたたき込んで
吐かせてみる？
Shall I punch her in the stomach to get her to spit it up?
That's no good! Once she ate it, it lost its form and became part of her!
無理なのです
レナに食べられて
形を失い 宿ってしまったのです
どうすんのよ！
何とかならないの？
Then what?! Can't we do something?!
紅白の勾玉をそろえ
古手(ふるで)神社の境内で―
If we can get both halves together at the Furude Shrine, then we could perform the removal ritual and she would be free.
解呪のおまじないをすれば
ちゃんと解けますです
Then it's easy. We'll just drag her down to the shrine on the way back. Problem solved.
なら簡単ね
帰りにレナを神社に連行して
一丁上がり
（羽入）ところが 白の勾玉が
一緒になきゃ解呪はできないのです
The problem is... we can't remove it unless the white jewel is there, too.
At this rate, Rena will fall in love with whomever
picks up the white jewel, whomever they may be!
このままではレナは―
白の勾玉を拾った人を
無差別に好きになって―
She'll go out of control, and sooner or later she'll go for a home run!
暴走して 既成事実とかで―
取り返しのつかないことに
なってしまうのですう！
You...!
あ～ん～た～！
Why the hell did you make something that dangerous?!
なんだって こんな危険なアイテム
作ったのよ！
１人で何をジタバタしてるのか
分かりませんけど―
I don't know what you're doing over there by yourself, but you know something about this, don't you, Rika?
何か知ってますのね？ 梨花
（梨花）み… みぃ
The Furude shrine treasure, "The Jewels of Accord"?
（圭一）“古手神社の至宝
フワラズの勾玉”!?
From this illustration, it looks just like a seal-shaped key-holder to me.
巻物の挿絵を見る限りじゃ―
オットセイのキーホルダーにしか
見えないね
赤を持つ人が白を持つ人を
好きになる… か
So the person who has the red one will fall in love with the person who has the white one?
Yes. Rena swallowed the red one. Therefore, if someone picks up the white one, Rena will be right there with it.
はいです レナは
その赤を飲み込んでしまいました
ですから 白を誰かが拾えば―
もれなく
レナもついてきちゃうわけなのです
And then they'll go all the way.
で ２人は既成事実… ってわけか
So, the problem now is: who picked up the white seal?
問題は 白のオットセイを
誰が拾ったかだね
I already know the answer. Look at that!
分かりましたのです ほら あれ！
It's a photography magazine!
写真撮影の専門誌ですわよ！
There's only one person in Hinamizawa whom that could refer to.
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)で あのキーワードが
意味する人物は…
Um, Mii-chan? Rena is feeling a bit sick all of a sudden, so she'll be going home early, okay?
あのね 魅ぃちゃん
レナは急に具合が悪くなったから
早退するね
うおお！ ちょ… ちょっとレナ！
（ドアの開閉音）
Hey, Rena!
So what do we do now?
どういたしますの!?
（魅音）えっ
At this rate they're headed straight for a home run!
このままでは
既成事実にまっしぐらでしてよ！
Anyway, we're just going to have to get our hands on the white jewel!
とにかく 白い勾玉を
押さえるしかない！
All right. Let's go, everyone!
よし 行くよ みんな！
（圭一たち）おう！
You'll teach Rena all about cameras and also
about other things, too... Won't you? Won't you?
（鷹野）あ…
（レナ）レナ カメラのこととか―
カメラ以外のこととか
いろいろ教えてほしいかな かな
カカ… カメラ以外のことって
何かな？ ハハッ ハハハッ
W-What do you mean by 'other' things?
Jirou-san! Aren't you good at teaching people
about "other things", even if you're not asked?!
ジロウさん カメラ以外のこと―
聞いてもいないのに教えてくれるの
得意だもんねえ
レナ 富竹さんなら その…
Tomitake-san, if it's you teaching, Rena... um... is willing to learn anything.
どんなこと教えてくれても
いいかな かな
いやっ ハハハ アハハッ
T-There she is!
い… いたあ！
Rena! Wake up! Those feelings of yours are a lie!
レ… レナ 目を覚ませ！
レナのその気持ちは偽物なんだあ！
ううっ 偽物なんてひどいよ！
A lie?! That's a terrible thing to say!
レナはね 気づいちゃったの
富竹さんの本当の優しさ！
I've realized Tomitake-san's true kindness!
だからもうレナには
富竹さんしかいないの！
He's the only one Rena needs now!
ハァ～ ハハ～…
ぼぼぼ… 僕には鷹野さんという
パートナーがいるんだ
I have a p-partner by the name of Takano-san already... so...
だから その…
鷹野さんは富竹さんのお友達でしょ
Isn't Takano-san just your friend?
お… お友達!? ホーッホッホッホ…
F-Friend?!
It seems Rena-chan doesn't understand adult relationships yet!
レナちゃんには まだ
大人の関係は理解できないようね
分かりますよーだ
（鷹野）んっ！
I do, too!
Come on, Tomitake-san, if you want, I'll even dress up as a nurse and model for you.
ねえ 富竹さ～ん
レナ 富竹さんが望むなら―
看護師さんの格好で
モデルになってあげてもいいのにい
ええっ！
ぼ… 僕には鷹野さんが…
I have T-Takano-san-
看護師姿を何度お願いしても―
Do you really prefer someone who won't dress up as a nurse, no matter how much you ask?
ちっともオッケーしてくれない
人のほうがいいんですか？
J-Jirou-san wouldn't say anything like that!
そ… そんなことを
ジロウさんが言うはずないでしょ！
ウソだっっ！
LIES!
（鷹野）キャア！
（富竹）えっ！ うっ…
Rena knows.
（レナ）レナは知ってるよ
Tomitake-san doesn't want to take pictures of birds.
富竹さんは
野鳥が撮りたいんじゃない
鷹野さんが撮りたいんだよ
He wants to take pictures of you, Takano-san!
But you won't let him at all. Somebody cruel like that is a failure as a partner!
でも 鷹野さんは
ちっとも撮らせてあげない
そんな意地悪な人は
パートナー失格なの
だからレナが！
（鷹野･富竹）あっ
That's why Rena will...!
Take Tomitake-san...!
（レナ）富竹さんを…
（鷹野･富竹）あっ！
Home!
お持ち帰り～！
Hey, Tomitake-san, which nurse outfit do you like more? White or pink? Which one?
（レナ）ねえ 富竹さ～ん
看護師さんの服 白いのとピンクの
どっちが好きかな？ かな？
（富竹）ワオッ！ ウハハ～！
シュッシュッ ポッポッ
シュッシュッ ポッポッ…
Fine! I don't care! Just go teach her whatever, Jirou-san!
（鷹野）もう知らないわ！
ジロウさんは レナちゃんに
いろいろ教えてあげるといいのよ！
ああ 失礼しちゃう 失礼しちゃう！
Satoko! Are you ready?
（圭一）沙都子 準備はいいか？
（沙都子）
オーケーですわ いきますわよ！
Okay! Here we go!
今だ 発射ー！
（沙都子）ポチッとな
Now! Fire!
Poke!
Let's grab the jewel from him while we can.
今のうちに富竹さんから
勾玉を取り返すんだ
フウ おかしいな 見つからないぜ
That's weird. It's not here. He does have it, right?
富竹さんが持ってるんだよな？
（梨花）あっ
Tomitake doesn't have it!
富竹は持ってないのです
（梨花）も… 持ってない!?
He doesn't?!
（圭一）くう～ 持ってない！
He doesn't have it!
じゃあレナは？
（圭一）あっ
Then where's Rena?
あっ！ いつの間にか
いなくなっていますわ！
She disappeared!
（梨花）
って 新しい勾玉の持ち主の所へ
行ったってこと!?
Which means she went to whomever has the jewel now?!
（鷹野）ああもう 不愉快だわ！
ほんっとに不愉快！
Jeez! This is getting on my nerves! Really, now!
I mean, if Jirou-san really, really wanted it, I might just let him take pictures of me in my work outfit...
そりゃ私だって ジロウさんが
どうしてもって言うなら―
お仕事の服で
被写体になってあげてもいいけど…
ああん！
でも そんなの恥ずかしい！
But it's sooo embarrassing!
あっ でも
どうしてもって言うなら…
But if he really wanted it...
うわあ～！
きき… 聞いてたかしら!?
D-D-D-D-Did you hear any of that?
Nope, not a word.
ううん 聞いてませんよ
あっ な… なあに？ 何か用なの？
W-What? Is there something you wanted to speak with me about?
はぅ～ レナ
本当はその… えっと…
Um... Er... Rena, um...
んっ なあに？
What is it?
The one I really love is you, Miyo-san!
本当に大好きなのは
三四(みよ)さんなんです！
あっ… そんなにくっつかれても…
You don't need to get that close...
Rena's eyes have always been drawn to you!
レナは ずっと三四さんだけを
見続けてきたんです
ああ 三四さんのことを
お姉様と呼んでみたい！
I want to call you Onee-sama!
I want to be your little sister!
三四さんの妹になりたい
三四さんに毎朝―
Every morning, I want you to tell me, "Your scarf is crooked", and have you fix it for me!
タイが曲がっていてよって
直してもらいたい～！
あっ あのね 私―
Ah, um, you see, people often get me wrong. However, I'm not that kind of-
よーく誤解されるんだけど
そういう趣味は ぜーんぜん…
ウソだっ！
（鷹野）ひいい！
LIES!
Rena's seen that disgusted look in your eyes whenever you look at men.
レナには分かるんです
三四さんが男を見る時の
あの汚らわしそうな目つき
男なんて しょせんはケダモノ
Men are nothing more than beasts.
人とケダモノが
分かり合えるはずなんかないんです
There's no way humans and beasts can understand each other!
But Rena and Miyo-san can.
でも レナと三四さんは
分かり合える
I want to do the real Watanagashi with you, Miyo-san!
私 三四さんと
本当の綿流しがしたい
I want to cut open the sacrifices' chests with you! I do! I do!
一緒に いけにえのおなかを
裂きたい！ かな かな～
（沙都子）んっ ハッ
（圭一）ていっ！
ああ アハハ
あっ すみませんね 鷹野さん
Sorry for that, Takano-san. It seems that Rena's brain thinks it's spring, so...
ちょいとレナの頭の中に
春が来ちゃったみたいで その…
春？ 春って何の話？
（魅音）いや アハ…
Spring? What are you talking about?
What Rena's saying right now is against her own will, so, um...
（圭一）今 レナが口走ってるのは
本人の意思とは関係ないことでして
ええ その…
んっ！ お黙りなさい
この雄ザルが～！
SILENCE, YOU APE!
（魅音）ひいい！
レナちゃん 今こそ私は気づいたわ
そうよ そうだったのよ！
Rena-chan, I've finally realized; yes, it's true!
ジロウさんと一緒にいても
満たされない何かを―
Thanks to you, I've found what was always missing when I was with Jirou-san!
私は あなたのおかげで―
ようやく理解したわ！
（沙都子たち）はっ？
（圭一たち）あっ…
（レナ）三四さん
Miyo-san...
All right, all right, no hugging.
はいはい 抱擁は禁止ですわよ
（圭一）どわっ くっ
（魅音）うわっ！
W-We were too late...!
お… 遅かったか
（鷹野）
ビシッ レナちゃん さあ―
Come now, Rena-chan, let's bring about Oyashiro-sama's curse together!
２人で一緒に オヤシロさまの
祟(たた)りを引き起こしましょう！
そして２人は
永遠に寄り添い合うのよ
And then we shall be together forever!
（レナ）
あーん 三四さ～ん！
Ah, Miyo-san! May I call you Onee-sama from this day on?
At this rate, we'll have the Hinamizawa disaster by tomorrow night!
このままじゃ 明日の晩は
雛見沢大災害なのです
今日から
三四さんのこと―
このままじゃ 明日の晩は
雛見沢大災害なのです
お姉様って
呼んでいいですか？
We need to get that jewel back as soon as possible!
一刻も早く
勾玉を取り返すのです
（鷹野）そうね
特別に許してあげるわ
Hmm, as a special treat, I shall allow it!
ですわね
That's right...
（レナ）
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
The white seal key-holder you have - it's Rika's. Give it back to her!
（沙都子）あなたがお持ちの
白いオットセイのキーホルダー
あれは梨花のですのよ
お返しなさいませ！
This belongs to Rika-chan?
これ 梨花ちゃんのなの？
（魅音）そう
Right! That's one of the Furude shrine's treasures!
それは 古手神社の
大切な宝物なんだから！
あっ バカ 魅音！ 鷹野さんに
そんなこと言ったら…
Wait! Mion! Don't say that to Takano-san!
One of the Furude shrine's treasures...?
（鷹野）古手神社の大切な宝物？
オーッホホホホ…
Now that I've heard that, I can't just hand it over now, can I?
そうと聞いてしまったら
簡単に返すわけにはいかないわね
Come, Rena-chan, let's thoroughly investigate this treasure together!
さあ レナちゃん
私たちで
この神秘のお宝を徹底究明よ！
あっ ちょっと返しなさいって！
Wait, give it back!
はぅ～ ダメだよ
三四さんのあとは追わせないよ
Stop right there! I won't let you chase Miyo-san!
レナ！ そこをどけえ！
（レナ）はぅっ！
Rena! Clear the way!
（圭一たち）どひゃ…
（魅音）ずしゃ
（羽入）今のレナは最強なのですう
Rena is unstoppable as she is now!
Onee-sama! Rena's coming too!
お姉様 レナも一緒に行くよお
The clinic... we've got to go to...
（沙都子）し… 診療所ですわ
診療所に… 行くのです
the clinic...
Hmm, that's odd... Where'd I put that jewel?
（鷹野）あら～ おかしいわねえ
あの勾玉
どこやったのかしら？ あららら
Aw! I'm such a klutz!
もう 私のバカー！
It looks like she somehow managed to lose the jewel.
（沙都子）こともあろうに
勾玉を落としちゃったようですわよ
That means Rena won't come here?
（圭一）ってことは レナのやつは
ここには来ないってことか
（梨花）捜すのです
（圭一）行くぞ！
Let's look for her!
Let's go!
んっ いないぞ
（魅音）どこ行ったんだろ？
She's not here...
Where'd she go...?
あっ ご覧なさいませ
あんな本が！
Look over there! That book...!
What kind of book is it this time?
（圭一）今度は何の本だ？ ん？
Hm... Modern Washizu Mahjong?
「現代 鷲巣麻雀(わしずマージャン)」
「哭(な)きの竜が如(ごと)く」「麻雀放浪譚(たん)」
Like a crying dragon?
Mahjong Houroutan?
They're all mahjong books?
みんなマージャンの本？
W-What'd you say?!
な… 何ですってえ!?
（男性）ほほう
（男性）ハハ やってられねえよ
I suppose it's about time for me to declare riichi now.
Note: riichi is declaring that you're one tile away from winning.
（赤坂(あかさか)）
そろそろリーチさせてもらいますよ
ようやく いい牌(はい)が入ってきたので
I've finally got a good hand.
ウソだっ！
LIES!
（赤坂）うわあ！ 何？
W-What?!
（レナ）レナは知ってるよ
Rena knows. Akasaka-san has, for the past five turns, just been pretending to improve his hand.
赤坂さんは５巡前から
手牌を進めるフリをしてるけど―
But in reality, he's just continuing to discard his draws.
実はツモ牌をそのまま切ってるだけ
Why are you now suddenly talking about declaring a riichi? Why?
なのに どうしてここに来て
急にリーチなのかな？ かな？
（大石(おおいし)）ハハハッ こりゃ驚いた
Well, this is a surprise! Ryuuguu-san, you're quite good at mahjong, aren't you?
竜宮(りゅうぐう)さん なかなか
マージャンお強いじゃないですか
やりますねえ
You totally had me there.
さっきマンガ読んで勉強したんです
I read a bit of manga to study it up a bit. I just wanted to play with Ooishi-san...
大石さんと一緒に遊びたくてえ
アハハッ
It looks like I've finally come to channel the looks of a green dandy!
いやあ とうとう私にも―
ミドルのダンディーな魅力が
宿ったということでしょうかねえ
ナハッ ナハハハハッ…
（圭一）んっ いたあ！
There she is!
Hanyuu! Are you sure this time?!
（梨花）
羽入 今度こそ間違いない？
（羽入）
あぅあぅ 間違いありません
大石は今 懐に持っていますのです
No doubt about it! Ooishi has it in his pocket right now!
（梨花）大石
（大石）んっ？
Ooishi, did you pick up a white seal-shaped key-holder in Hinamizawa today?
今日 雛見沢で―
白いオットセイのキーホルダーを
拾いませんでしたか？
Yeah... I did.
（大石）ああ 確かに拾いましたよ
That's Rika's! Give it back!
それは梨花のなんですのよ
さっさとお返しなさいですわ！
そうそう その勾玉のせいで
レナがこんなになっちゃってるの
Yeah! Thanks to that jewel, Rena's been all messed up lately!
What?! Stop! You don't need to tell him-!
あっ バカ！ 余計なことを…
（大石）えっ？
（魅音）ああ！
（大石）何ですって？
You don't say. Well now, if I gave this key-holder back, Ryuuguu-san would go home?
では このキーホルダーを
お返しすると―
竜宮さんは帰ってしまうわけですね
それは困ります
That won't work. I need her help to win back everything I've lost today.
これまでの負け分を
すべて取り返すまでは―
竜宮さんの協力が必要なんです
Not so fast! I'll be taking that back right now!
そうはいかねえぜ！
今すぐ そいつを返してもらうぜ！
（大石）どうしましょうかねえ
Hmm... Well now... How shall we handle this?
This is a mahjong parlour; we settle everything with mahjong here.
ここは雀荘で マージャンで
すべてを決着します ンフフ
（圭一）マ… マージャンで
決めるってことですか？
You mean, we'll decide this with a game of mahjong?
（大石）ンフフ～
Fine.
いいでしょう
はぅ～ ムダだと思うけどなあ
There's no point. Rena will always be with Ooishi-san!
レナは いつまでも
大石さんと一緒なの はぅ～
Idiot! Snap out of it! Those aren't your true feelings! You're just being blinded by that jewel!
バカ！ それはお前の本心じゃない
勾玉に惑わされてるだけなんだ！
（鑑識の爺様(じいさま)）ん？ ああ～！
（圭一）レナ！
Rena! I'll save you!
俺がお前を救ってやる！
TONPUUSEN
Very well then, let's have a tonpuusen to decide who gets the key-holder.
（大石）
それでは このオットセイの
キーホルダーをかけて―
東風(トンプー)戦 一発勝負と
いこうじゃないですか
So, a match between Keiichi's and Akasaka's team, vs Rena's and Ooishi-san's love-love team!
（レナ）じゃあ
圭一君と赤坂さんチーム対―
レナと大石さんの
ラブラブチームの対決だよ
The team in the #1 spot at the end wins!
終了時に
１位の人がいたチームが勝ち！
ってことは 自分がビリでも
相方が１位なら勝ちってわけだな
In other words, even if I'm in last place, if my partner's in first, we win, right?
A tonpuusen means that the dealer will rotate around only once - a short, decisive battle.
East
South
West
North
Note: All-last (Jap: オーラス) is the final round of the game. In normal mahjong, if the dealer wins or if he is in tenpai at the end of the game, he can remain as dealer.
東風戦ってことは―
親が１周したら
もうおしまいの短期決戦
The battle will all come down to how well the partners work with each other.
相方との相性のよさが
勝負を分けるってことだね
We'll go with the super-fast tonpuusen rules, and even if it's all last, the dealer won't keep his seat unless he wins.
In this match, however, the dealer has to win to keep himself in the dealer seat.
さくさくルールの東風戦で
上がらなければ―
ラス親でも流れちゃうってことで
いいですよね？
Fine!
い… いいですよ
Rika, Ooishi's hand is all messed up!
梨花 大石の手は
しっちゃかめっちゃかなのですよ
（梨花）全然
そろってないってこと？
You mean he hasn't assembled anything at all?
（羽入）そうなのです
That's right!
Keiichi, Ooishi hasn't put anything together yet!
圭一 大石は
全然そろってないのです
えっ！ よし
Eh?! All right...
ンフフフ ロン！
Ron!
ぎえ～！
（羽入）ああ！
（梨花）羽入 どうなってるのよ！
Hanyuu! What's going on here?!
But, but! Look, his hand's all messed up!!
だ… だってほら 大石の手は
めちゃくちゃなのです！
That's not like you at all, Maebara-san.
前原(まえばら)さんらしくもないですね
ンフフフッ…
Ooishi-san, you're amazing!
大石さん すごいよ はぅ～！
Mii... Rena's latent abilities are really amazing, aren't they?
みぃ それにしても―
レナの恐るべき潜在能力には
驚かされますのです
I'm quite amazed too. Normally, when you fall in love with
someone, don't you try to get them involved in your world?
おじさんもすごいと思うね
普通はさ
誰かを気に入ったらさ―
まず 自分の世界に
引き込もうとしない？
You try to get them to like what you like...
自分の好きなものを
気に入らせようとしたり
Isn't that normal?
それは普通じゃありませんの？
Rena's not like that. She does her best to align herself with her partner's interests.
レナは違うんだよね
相手の趣味に自分を合わせようと
一生懸命 努力する
That's got to be exhausting...
それって結構 疲れちゃいますわよ
ボクも相手を引き込むばかりで―
I, too, was always trying to drag my partner into my world, but I never tried stepping out myself...
自分から歩み寄ろうとしたことは
なかったかもなのです
It's the final battle.
ついに最後の勝負だね
わずかに圭一と赤坂のチームが
リードしているのです
Keiichi and Akasaka's team has a slight lead!
ということは―
Which means if they win or tie in this game, we'll be able to get the jewel back, right?
圭一さんたちが この勝負に勝つか
引き分けになれば―
勾玉は
取り戻せるということですわね
Yeah, that's it exactly.
ああ そういうこと
Akasaka's hand looks good! I'm sure it'll be worth a lot of points!
赤坂の手はとってもきれいなのです
きれいな手は点が高いのですよ
Akasaka-san can't bail out on his hand,
so Kei-chan needs to open the way for him!
赤坂さんは
勝負手で降りられない
なら 圭ちゃんが
露払いをするしかない
I'm counting on you, Keiichi-kun!
（赤坂）頼む 圭一君
All right, here I go!
（圭一）よし いきます
おりゃあ！
（圭一）くう… 通ったか？
Did I make it through...?
ンフフッ 残念 残念
Oh well.
はぅ～ 残念 残念
We'll be letting this discard pass.
通しです ンフフフッ
んっ それじゃ私も
Then I'll be discarding the same tile as well!
同じ牌を切らせていただきます
（大石）ぬおっ
（魅音）赤坂さん うまい！
Akasaka-san, nice one!
何がうまいのですか？
（魅音）マージャンはね―
What is?
In mahjong, there's a rule that says if you don't declare a win on a discard, you can't win on a discard of the same tile later.
一度上がりを見逃した牌じゃ
上がれないってルールがあるんだよ
なるほど！
I see!
Ryuuguu-san, it looks like we've been outed.
竜宮さん バレちゃってるようです
思いきって
リーチいっちゃいましょう
Let's just go for broke and riichi now.
はぅ～ レナもリーチ！
Rena will riichi too!
What should we do, Akasaka-san?
どうします？ 赤坂さん
（赤坂）よし 私もリーチです
All right, I'm declaring riichi, too.
はぅ～ レナと大石さんの―
Don't get in the way of our private riichi!
２人っきりのリーチを邪魔した
ブーブー
あっ ダブロンありなんですね！
（圭一）んっ？
This means there could be a double ron now!
圭ちゃん
Kei-chan, if you discard into a double ron, it's all over.
ここでダブルなんて振り込んだら
もう致命的だよ
分かってる
I know!
However, as Kei-chan's hand progresses, it'll get harder to
choose tiles to discard and it'll just get even more dangerous.
（魅音）
でも 圭ちゃんの手が
進めば進むほどに―
捨て牌を選べなくなって
危険度はどんどん上がる
I've realised that the tile with the chipped corner on the edge of the wall is Ooishi's winning tile!
ボクはさっきから ずっと
見ていたので分かりますのです
あの端っこの 角の欠けた牌は
大石の当たり牌なのです！
本当に？ 間違いなく？
で その牌は誰のツモになるの？
Seriously? You're sure?
So whose draw will that become?
（羽入）
１ ２ ３ ４ １ ２ ３ ４…
あぅ～っ まずいのです
1..2..3..4..1..2..3..4.. This isn't good! It'll be Akasaka's draw!
赤坂のツモになるのです！
Rika-chan's got a 'This is bad' look on her face.
梨花ちゃんが 何だか
まずいって顔してるよ
何かな？ 何かな？
What could it be? What could it be?
ンフフッ
握っちまったって顔ですね
That's a 'they've got us!' face, isn't it?
I see. So the enemy's draw has already been decided?
（赤坂）そうか
敵のツモが確定してるってことか
What should I do?
（圭一）
ど… どうすればいいんだよ
Eh? What is it, Mion?
Kei-chan, discard that and riichi.
（魅音）圭ちゃん
それを切ってリーチしよう
But if I do that...!
（圭一）
で… でも そんなことしたら…
（赤坂）いや 圭一君
（圭一）んっ
No, Keiichi-kun. There's no other choice if we want to win!
（赤坂）それしかない
勝つためには その手しか！
Damn it! Don't blame me if the worst happens!
ク… クソッ
どうなっても知らないからな
通らばリーチだ！
Tralala-riichi!
I-It made it through, right?!
と… 通ったね これでオッケー！
スーチャリーチでお流れだよ！
Good! Now it's a 4-player riichi draw.
Note: Special Rule: If all 4 players riichi, then the game draws, because it then becomes pure luck at this point.
は… はぅ～ お流れってことは
終わっちゃったの？
By a draw, you mean... it's over?
Aw, damn! If I had just gone out back then I would have definitely won!
ああ 残念！
私が上がれば確実に
いただきだったんですがねえ
Which means... Akasaka-san's the top scorer?
ってことは… ハッ！
（赤坂）フンッ
（圭一）赤坂さんがトップ！
We win!
俺たちの勝ちだあ！
（魅音たち）やったあ！
Yay!
ああ… はぅ～っ 負けちゃったあ
We lost...
いえいえ
勝負には負けましたが―
No, no... We might have lost the game,
but we were dominating the whole time.
ゲーム上は
私たちは終始優勢でしたよ
ほんっとに楽しいマージャンを
打たせてもらいましたよ
I had a great time playing mahjong with you.
Anyway, the promise was to return the key-holder, right?
ということで キーホルダーを
お返しする約束でしたね
Now that the stress has lifted, I'm feeling really tired all of a sudden.
緊張感が抜けたら
何だか急に眠くなってきたぜ
（あくび）
（大石）うわっと あっ！
んんっ ああ！
の… 飲み込んじまったあ！
I swallowed it?!
は… はあ？
何やってんの 圭ちゃん！
Eh?! What did you do, Kei-chan?! Spit it out! Satoko, grab his arms!
吐き出して 吐き出して！
沙都子 羽交い締めにして！
（沙都子）んっ くっ
（魅音）ドス ドス ドス ドス…
H-Hanyuu?
（魅音）
ドス ドス ドス ドス…
は… 羽入
（羽入）あぅ～
もっとドス ドス ドス
さらにドス ドス ドス…
Anyway, let's get them back to the shrine and lift the spell right away!
とにかく 圭一とレナを
古手神社に連れていって―
ドス ドス ドス ドス…
すぐに解呪するのです
よしっ 行くよ みんな！
（梨花･沙都子）おう！
All right! Let's go, everyone!
All right, Rena and Keiichi, don't move until I say it's okay.
（梨花）では レナと圭一
ボクがいいと言うまで
そのままなのですよ
（圭一）おう 分かったぜ
All right, understood.
Hey, Keiichi-kun?
ねえ 圭一君
（圭一）あっ？
Thanks for what you did back there.
さっきは その… ありがと
仲間を見捨てるもんかよ
I couldn't abandon my friend like that when she needed me.
I was... happy to hear those words.
あの時 圭一君が言ってくれた言葉
うれしかったかな
I'll save you!
俺がお前を助けてやる！
I really did hear them...
あの言葉 ちゃんと聞こえてたよ
べ… 別に 特別な意味で
言ったわけじゃねえぞ
T-There wasn't any hidden meaning behind them, you know.
（レナ）うん レナなんかに
しがみつかれたら迷惑だもんね
If someone like Rena kept clinging to you, it'd be a nuisance, wouldn't it?
（圭一）レナが嫌いだから
言ってるんじゃねえよ
I'm not saying I don't like you... It's just... those feelings you have should be directed to the person you truly do love.
あの恋するレナの気持ちは―
レナが本当に好きになった人に
向けられるべきで―
You shouldn't be forced to direct them at me because of this power.
こんな力で 俺なんかに
向けられるべきじゃない
そだね
Yeah, I guess...
But, you know, when Mii-chan was talking about how Rena was
so amazing for trying to match herself to her partner's interests...
でもね さっき魅ぃちゃんたちが
レナのことを―
相手に合わせられるのは
すごいって言ってたけど…
（圭一）ああ
（レナ）それって普通じゃないかな
Yeah?
Isn't that normal?
If someone falls in love, they'll try and work to make their partner like them.
誰だって 好きな人ができたら―
その人に気に入られようと
努力するよ
It's not that Rena has any special power.
レナだけの特別な力じゃないよ
Is that how it is?
そういうもんかねえ
（レナ）そ… そうだよ
（圭一）うっ
Y-Yeah.
はぅ～ ダ… ダメ 圭一君
It's no good, Keiichi-kun. The power of the Jewel of Accord is coming back up!
フワラズの勾玉の力
また こみ上げてきた
T-That's not good! A-Anyway, concentrate on your prayers!
ま… まずいな
とにかく お祈りに集中しろ
そうだね
I know...
Keiichi-kun, this might just be the jewel talking...
圭一君 これ―
勾玉の力なのかもしれないけど…
Um... Keiichi-kun... I love you.
あのね 竜宮レナは
圭一君のこと大好きだよ
If this power is going to disappear soon, I just want to make sure I told you.
もうすぐ消えちゃう力なら
今 それだけ伝えたいから
バ… バカ！
勾玉の力に屈するなよ
Stop it! Don't lose to the jewel's power!
んっ 本気にするだろ…
I might take you seriously...
そだね 勾玉の力
早く解けちゃうといいね
Yeah... I hope... the jewel's power fades soon...
Rena confessed to Keiichi!
レナが圭一に
告白しちゃいましたのです あぅ～！
Yeah, I heard. And for some reason that really pisses me off.
（梨花）ええ 聞こえたわ
なぜかムカムカして腹立たしいわ
あっ 魅音と沙都子には
聞こえなくて幸いだったのです
I'm glad Mion and Satoko didn't hear...
Oh well, anyway, with this everything's back to normal.
まあ これで一件落着なのです
ほんとに人騒がせなんだから
Way to cause a ruckus.
Wait, everything's not back to normal!!
（梨花）
って 一件落着してな～い！
Didn't you promise me yesterday?
（富竹）
昨日 僕と約束したじゃないか！
ほら レナちゃんのサイズで
ちゃんとナース服を用意したんだ！
I got a nurse uniform in your size ready for you!
さあ 僕と２人っきりの
プライベート撮影会だよ
Come on, we'll have a private photo shoot, just the two of us!
（鷹野）
ちょっと放しなさいよ ジロウさん
Let go, Jirou-san! Rena-chan isn't interested in a filthy baboon like you!
レナちゃんはね 汚らわしい
雄ザルになんて興味ないんだから！
（富竹）
レナちゃん はい はい…
ねえ？ レナちゃん
Oh, yes, Rena-chan, from now on, you can call me 'Onee-sama'.
そうそう 今日から私のことは
お姉様って呼んでいいんだからね
Oh, dear, your scarf is crooked.
ほらほら ダメよ
タイが曲がっていてよ フフフッ
Stop standing there and help me!
（レナ）なんで
こんな目に遭うのかな？ かな？
（鷹野）
ああ！ ちょっと
やめてよ ジロウさん
Someone save me!
（富竹）ほらほら
早く早く早く…
誰か助けて～！
（鷹野）１人撮影会
してればいいでしょ！
That's not the power of the jewel, so there's nothing more I can do.
あれは 勾玉の力ではないので―
（鷹野）１人撮影会
してればいいでしょ！
もうボクには
どうしようもないのです
けじめを取るため 今日は３食―
もう
ジロウさんったら！
So, to repent, I'll have to eat a parfait of kimchi, wasabi, and mustard for every meal today!
キムチとワサビとマスタードの
パフェを食べまくるのです
あぅ～ あぅ～！ 梨花の鬼！
鬼畜～！
Rika, you demon! You brute!
痛くないように、やさしく危めた
I gently ended , to stop the pain...
itakunai you ni, yasashiku ayameta
言葉に置き換えて、悲しみを忘れて
Changing it into mere words, I forget the sadness...
kotoba ni okikaete, kanashimi wo wasurete
あぁ、今、何を亡くしたのだろう？
But, ah, what have I now lost?
aa, ima, nani wo nakushita no darou?
罪という音の並びから　思い描かれた
Pictured by the sounds of my sins,
tsumi to iu oto no narabi kara  omoiegakareta
償うことも叶わない夢の記憶
this never-to-be-redeemed dream of a memory
tsugunau koto mo kanawanai yume no kioku
望まれたこの世界から　消えてなくなった・・・
vanished from this world that I had always longed for...
nozomareta kono sekai kara  kietenakunatta...
いつも既にかけている　人の祈り・・・
I have always been saying a human prayer...
itsumo sudeni kaketeiru  hito no inori...